Finding aid for Library (University of Michigan) Records, 1837 - 2013
Bentley Historical Library
- Other Offices and Projects, 1904-2004
  - Library Information Technology (LIT), 1985-2002; 1993-2002
    - Michigana, 2001 (Box 281)
    - Middle English Compendium (MEC; note: also known as the Middle English Dictionary), 1997; 1999-2001 (Box 281)
    - Minerva, 1996 (Box 281)
    - M-Stor, 2000 (Box 281)
    - Museum Education Site Learning (MESL) (Box 282)
      - Content, 1998-1999 (Box 282)
      - Evaluation, 1997 (Box 282)
      - License, 1995-1997 (Box 282)
      - Meetings, 1996 (Box 282)
      - University of Michigan, 1994-1999 (Box 282)
    - Museum Project, 1999 (Box 282)
    - Music Library, 1998-1999 (Box 282)
    - My Library, 2001 (Box 282)
    - National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH)
      - Amverse, 1998 (Box 282)
      - Philippines, 1999-2001 (Box 282)
      - Seeing the Body Elsewise, 1999-2000 (Box 282)
    - National Science Foundation (NSF)
      - General, 1993-1996 (Box 282)
      - Agents, 1996 (Box 282)
      - Collections, 1994-1996 (Box 282)
      - Digital Library Initiative (DLI) International, 1998-1999 (Box 282)
      - Digital Library Initiative (DLI) II Planning, 1998 (Box 282)
      - Math Digital Library (DL), 2000 (Box 282)
      - New York Public Library (NYPL), 1994-1997 (Box 282)
      - Reports, 1994-1998 (Box 282)
    - Network Upgrade, 2000-2001 (Box 282)
    - Networked Information Steering Committee (NISC), 1996-1999 (Box 282)
    - Networked Resources Technical Alert (NRT Alert), 1999 (Box 282)
    - NOTIS Contract, 1987; 1991 (Box 282)
    - Numeric Data
      - 1998-1999 (Box 282)
      - 1999-2000 (Box 282)
      - 2000-2001 (Box 282)
    - Open Text, 1990-1999 (scattered) (Box 282)
    - OVID Implementation, 1996-1999; 2 folders (Box 282)
    - Patents, 1995-1997 (Box 283)
    - Pictures of Record, 1998-2000 (Box 283)
    - Population Studies Center, 2000 (Box 283)
    - Porgy and Bess, 1998 (Box 283)
    - Presidential Commission Reports, 2000-2002; 2 folders (Box 283)
    - Pricing Electronic Access to Knowledge (PEAK)
      - General, 1997-1998 (Box 283)
      - Accounting and Billing, 1997-1998 (Box 283)
      - American Library Association (ALA)
        - June 1998 (Box 283)
        - January 1999 (Box 283)
      - Committee on Institutional Cooperation (CIC), 1996-1997 (Box 283)
      - Current, 1997-1999 (Box 283)
      - Economic Models, 1996-1997 (Box 283)
      - Economics and Use of Digital Library Collections Conference, 2000 (Box 283)
      - Elsevier Communication, 1995-1998 (Box 283)
      - Elsevier License, 1996-1998 (Box 283)
      - Extension, 1998 (Box 283)
      - Papers/Presentations, 1997-1999 (Box 283)
      - Pricing Electronic Access to Knowledge (PEAK) Group, 1997-1998 (Box 283)
      - Sites
        - Dow Chemical Company, 1997-1999 (Box 283)
        - Drexel University, 1998 (Box 283)
        - Indiana University, 1997-1999 (Box 283)
        - Lehigh University, 1997-1999 (Box 283)
        - Michigan Technological University (MTU; Michigan Tech), 1997-1999 (Box 283)
        - Minnesota, University of, 1997-1999 (Box 283)
        - Parke-Davis Pharmaceutical Research, 1997-1999 (Box 283)
        - Philadelphia College of Pharmacy and Science (PCPS), 1998 (Box 283)
        - Texas A & M University, 1996-1999 (Box 283)
        - Vanderbilt University, 1998-1999 (Box 283)
      - Sites Offers, 1996-1998 (Box 283)
      - System Development (Box 283)
    - Print on Demand, no date (Box 283)
    - Printing, 1996-2000; 2 folders (Box 283)
    - Privacy, 1987-1988; 1999-2000 (Box 284)
    - Publishing Initiative -- Iowa, 2000 (Box 284)
    - Publishing Proposal, 1998-2001 (Box 284)
    - Regents Proceedings, 2000 (Box 284)
    - Research Computing Advisory Committee (RCAC)
      - 1996 (Box 284)
      - 1997 (Box 284)
      - 1998-1999 (Box 284)
    - Research Libraries Group (RLG), 1998 (Box 284)
    - Reserves, 1998-1999 (Box 284)
    - Routledge, 1999 (Box 284)
    - Salaries, 1995-1998 (Box 284)
    - Security, 1997-2001; 2 folders (Box 284)
    - Share Space Task Force, 2000 (Box 284)
    - Small Publishers Group, 1998 (Box 284)
    - Software Assessment Center, 1998 (Box 284)
    - Space, 1996 (Box 284)
    - Sunrise Media, 1998-1999 (Box 284)
    - Sunsite, 1999 (Box 284)
    - Table of Contents (TOC) Services, 1997 (Box 284)
    - Text Encoding Initiative (TEI), 1998; 2 folders (Box 284)
    - Tulip, 1992-1995 (Box 284)
    - University of Michigan Encyclopedic History, 1999 (Box 284)
    - University of Michigan Instructional Environment (UMIE), 1996-1997 (Box 284)
    - University of Michigan Research Environment (UMRE), 1997 (Box 284)
    - Value Centered Management (VCM), 1996 (Box 284)
    - Vice-President for Research, Office of (OVPR), 1998-1999 (Box 284)
    - Virtual Libraries Conference, 1999 (Box 284)
    - Virtual University, 1996 (Box 284)
    - Visual Resources Online, 1999 (Box 284)
    - Web Architecture
      - 1998-1999 (Box 284)
      - 1999-2000 (Box 284)
    - Web Feat, 2000 (Box 284)
    - Wetzel Collection, 1997-1999 (Box 284)
    - Xerox, 1994-1997 (Box 284)
  - Loup, Jean Files, 1977-2001; 1992-2001
    The Loup, Jean Files series, 1977-2001 (bulk 1992-2001) is organized alphabetically and contains files related to the career and activities of librarian Jean Loup. Loup held several different offices and roles during her time with the University Library including assistant to the library dean, head of the Department of Communications, Public Relations, and Grant Writing, chair of the Academic Affairs Advisory Committee (AAAC), library delegate to the Senate Assembly, vice-chair and chair of the Senate Advisory Committee on University Affairs (SACUA), and leader in many projects including M-Quality (Regent's Proceedings). Topics that are particularly well-documented in this series include the AAAC (especially during Loup's tenure as chair), and M-Quality, a campus-wide initiative designed to encourage continuous improvement in everyday tasks (Record article).
    - Academic Affairs Advisory Committee (AAAC) (Box 285)
      - Agendas and Minutes
        - 1998-1999 (Box 285)
        - 2000-2001 (Box 285)
      - Chair, 1999-2000 (Box 285)
      - Deans Evaluation, 1994-2000 (Box 285)
      - Future of the Faculty and the University, 1998-1999 (Box 285)
      - North Central Association Accreditation Self Study, 1999-2000 (Box 285)
      - Reproductive Sciences Program, 1999-2000 (Box 285)
      - Teaching Principles
        - Background Documents, 1999-2000 (Box 285)
        - Documents and Drafts, 2001 (Box 285)
      - Tenure Committee Proposals, 1999-2000 (Box 285)
    - Administrative Meetings, 1999-2000 (Box 285)
    - American Association of University Professors (AAUP) Governance Conference, 196 (Box 285)
    - Association of College and Research Libraries (ACRL): Detroit, 1999 (Box 285)
    - Bollinger, 1997 (Box 285)
    - Classification Evaluation Committee Correspondence, 1977-1978 (Box 285)
    - Colclazer Event, 1998 (Box 285)
    - Copyright Seminar, 1996-1997; 2 folders (Box 285)
    - Copyright Symposium Correspondence, 1997-1998 (Box 285)
    - Correspondence
      - General, 1982-1992 (Box 285)
      - Gosling, William, January-May 1997 (Box 285)
    - Delphi Study (Westbrook, Lynn), Spring 1992 (Box 285)
    - Dentistry Library, 1998 (Box 285)
    - Development Brain-Storming, 1997-1998 (Box 285)
    - Discussions on Cooperative Collection Development: University of Michigan, Michigan State (MSU), and Western Michigan (WMU) Universities, 1992 (Box 285)
    - Electronic Journals Survey from Ohio State University (OSU), October 1997 (Box 285)
    - Faculty Leadership Questionnaire, 1995-1996 (Box 285)
    - Future of the University Library, 1995-1996 (Box 285)
    - Graduate Library Focus Group, 1992-1993 (Box 285)
    - Illinois, University of -- Data Request, November 1997 (Box 285)
    - Jewels in the Crown, 1997-1998 (Box 285)
    - Korean Studies Program, 1998 (Box 285)
    - Librarian Meeting with James J. Duderstadt, Provost, February 1998 (Box 285)
    - Library Dean Search, 1996 (Box 285)
    - Lobbying Report, 1998-1999 (Box 285)
    - Making of America (MOA), 1995-1998 (Box 285)
    - Making the Library a Better Place, 1993 (Box 285)
    - Miscellaneous, 1990-2000; 2 folders (Box 286)
    - Monthly Reports, 1997-1998 (Box 286)
    - M-Quality
      - General, 1995-1997 (Box 286)
      - Document Delivery Team, 1993-1995 (Box 286)
      - Holdings Team, 1994 (Box 286)
      - Kahn Article, 1993 (Box 286)
      - Lead Team Charge, 1992-1993 (Box 286)
      - Library Teams, 1992-1994 (Box 286)
      - New Serials Team, 1993-1994 (Box 286)
      - Orientation, 1992 (Box 286)
      - Rush Process Team, 1994-1998 (Box 286)
      - Student Hiring Team
        - 1992-1994 (Box 286)
        - 1994-1995 (Box 286)
      - Survey, 1996 (Box 286)
      - Team Leader Training, 1992-1993 (Box 286)
    - Oral History Project with Mona East, 1985 (Box 286)
    - Overberger Committee, 1979-1980 (Box 286)
    - Photographs: Senate Advisory Committee on University Affairs (SACUA), no date (Box 286)
    - PSYCNews, 1991-1992 (Box 286)
    - Public Health Library, 1990 (Box 286)
    - Samors Meeting, 1997-1998 (Box 286)
    - Science Library Notes, 1998 (Box 286)
    - Senior Managers
      - 1997-1998 (Box 286)
      - 1999-2000 (Box 286)
    - Strategies for the 1994-1997 Strategic Plan, April 1995 (Box 286)
    - Sullivan/Clack Workshop, August 1993 (Box 286)
    - Swiss Exhibit, 1993-1994 (Box 286)
    - Theft Work, 1996-1997 (Box 286)
    - TQ-103 Fortune University, 1994 (Box 286)
    - Wagman Memorial, 1994 (Box 286)
    - Washington, D.C. Trip, April 1994 (Box 286)
    - Winston, Mark: Association of Research Libraries (ARL) Article, 1998 (Box 286)
  - Internship programs
    The Internship programs series, 1982-1990, 0.3 linear feet, contains planning and policy documents related to the Research Library Residency and University Library Associates programs.
    - Research Librarian Currricula, 1985-1990 (Box 294)
    - Research Library Residency Program Planning Materials, 1982-1990 (Box 294)
    - University Library Associates Program Planning Materials, 1987-1990 (Box 294)
- Human Resources, 1956-2001; 1970-1996
  The Human Resources series is organized into three sub-series: Staff Handbooks, Library Position Classifications, and Internship Programs.
  - Staff Handbooks, 1956-1981
    The Staff Handbooks subseries, 1956-1987, traces the evolution of library policies from the late 1950s to the mid-1980s. The staff manuals were regularly updated as library policies, such as purchasing books, library keys, and authorizing travel funds, changed. The manuals detail changing procedures for Administration, Collection Development, Personnel, Reader Services, Special Staff Circulation, and Technical Services. Organizational Charts are included in the Staff Manuals.
    - Library Staff Manual, 1956-1981 (Box 291)
    - Staff Manual 1, (Folder 1), 1958-1987 (Box 291)
    - Staff Manual 1, (Folder 2), 1958-1987 (Box 291)
    - Staff Manual 1, (Folder 3), 1958-1987 (Box 291)
    - Faculty Handbook, Primary Library Staff, (Folder 1), 1958-1987 (Box 291)
    - Faculty Handbook, Primary Library Staff, (Folder 2), 1958-1987 (Box 291)
    - Faculty Handbook, Primary Library Staff, (Folder 3), 1958-1987 (Box 291)
  - Library Position Classifications, 1963-1991
    The Library Position Classifications subseries, 1963-1991(bulk 1971-1979), is organized alphabetically and chronologically. Administrative files are arranged alphabetically and precede position description materials. Administrative files detail the position evaluation process and reconsideration requests. Position description materials are organized chronologically. Records contain detailed descriptions of job summary, work performed, periodic duties, job qualifications, education, and experience. During the 1970s, the library went through a significant restructuring period. The records in this sub-series shed light on the changing needs of the library and its staff.
    - Classification Evaluation Committee Correspondence, 1977-1979 (Box 291)
    - Classification of Librarians (Box 291)
    - Evaluation Committee Documents, 1977 (Box 291)
    - Executive Committee Reconsideration Requests, 1972-1976 (Box 291)
    - Position Reports, 1971-1973 (Box 291)
    - Staff Retention, 1989-1991 (Box 291)
    - Library Extension Service Position Descriptions, 1963-1974 (Box 291)
    - Undergraduate Library Position Descriptions, 1971-1973 (Box 291)
    - Divisional Libraries Position Descriptions, 1971-1973 (Box 291)
    - Divisional Libraries Position Descriptions, 1971-1974 (Box 291)
    - Public Services Descriptions, Old System, 1972 (Box 291)
    - Medical Center Library Position Descriptions, 1972-1973 (Box 291)
    - Executive Committee Classification Evaluations, 1972-1974 (Box 291)
    - Technical Services Description, Old System, (Folder 1), 1972-1976 (Box 291)
    - Technical Services Description, Old System, (Folder 2), 1972-1976 (Box 291)
    - Superseded Position Descriptions, Old System, 1972-1977 (Box 292)
    - Old System Position Descriptions, Outside Libraries, 1973-1976 (Box 292)
    - Graduate Library Position Descriptions, 1973-1974 (Box 292)
    - Selected Bibliographies, 1973-1975 (Box 292)
    - Non-System Library Jobs Evaluations, 1975-1977 (Box 292)
    - Position Classification Worksheets, 1976-1979 (Box 292)
    - Eliminated Position Descriptions, New System, 1977-1979 (Box 292)
  - Internship Programs, 1983-2001
    The Internship Programs subseries, 1983-2001, is organized chronologically. The records highlight two programs: Research Library Residency Program and Library Minority Training Internship Program (LM TIP or TIP). The Internship Programs subseries includes photographs and negatives in Box 293.
    Records for the Research Library Residency Program highlight the internal proposal process, recruitment, and seminar series associated with the residency program. Research Library Residents held a two-year, non-continuing professional appointment. The residency program included a Seminar Series created to introduce residents to the wide range issues shaping research libraries. Records include materials from the recruitment process, library division proposals, resident application materials, seminar materials, and seminar exit surveys.
    Library Minority Training Internship Program's (LM TIP) records detail the origins of the program as well as some of the challenges faced by minority library staff. LM TIP was developed to recruit, train, and mentor people of color for library positions. The program sought a diverse pool of applicants not only from the University of Michigan Personnel sources, but also from local churches, campus organizations, and multi-cultural organizations throughout Southeastern Michigan. Internship positions ran between 9 months and 2 years.
    - Research Library Residency Program Pamphlets, 1986-1988 (Box 292)
    - Research Library Residency Program Proposal Guidelines, 1983-1985 (Box 292)
    - Research Library Residency Program Proposals, (Folder 1), 1983-1986 (Box 292)
    - Research Library Residency Program Proposals, (Folder 2), 1983-1986 (Box 292)
    - Resident Recruitment, 1983-1986 (Box 292)
    - Residency Interviewing, 1983-1987 (Box 292)
    - Residency Seminar, November 3, 1983 (Box 292)
    - Residency Seminar, November 10, 1983 (Box 292)
    - Residency Seminar, November 17, 1983 (Box 292)
    - Research Library Residency Seminar, 1983 (Box 292)
    - Research Library Residency Seminars, 1984-1985 (Box 292)
    - Role of Public Service Librarians, April 26, 1985 (Box 292)
    - Library Administrative Issues, May 15 and 17, 1985 (Box 292)
    - Residency Monthly Reports, 1985 (Box 293)
    - Research Library Resident Seminars, 1986 (Box 293)
    - Residency Seminar Survey, (Folder 1), 1984-1987 (Box 293)
    - Residency Seminar Survey, (Folder 2), 1984-1987 (Box 293)
    - Library Resident Program Photographs (Box 293)
    - Library Resident Program Negatives (Box 293)
    - Research Library Residency Program, (Folder 1), 1998-2001 (Box 293)
    - Research Library Residency Program, (Folder 2), 1998-2001 (Box 293)
    - Research Library Residency Program, Residents Hired, 1998-2000 (Box 293)
    - Residency Recruitment, Applicants/No Interview, 1998-2001 (Box 293)
    - LA II/III LMTIP, 1990-1992 (Box 293)
    - TIP Funding OMA, 1990-1994 (Box 293)
    - LMTIP Pilot, 1990-1995 (Box 293)
    - TIP Training Program, 1990-1998 (Box 293)
    - TIP Engineering, 1992-1995 (Box 293)
    - TLA I Pilot LMTIP, 1994 (Box 293)
    - LM TIP, 1994-1995 (Box 293)
    - TIP Cataloging, 1994-1996 (Box 293)
    - TIP Interviews, 1996 (Box 293)
    - LM TIP Proposals, 1996 (Box 293)
    - LM TIP Packets, 1996 (Box 293)
    - LM TIP Clerical Recruitment, 1996-1997 (Box 293)
    - LM TIP Training Internship, 1996 (Box 293)
    - LM TIP, 1997 (Box 293)
Selective Index to Corespondents
This index provides a selective listing to correspondents in the Director's Files, 1905-1950.
Angell, James Burrill, 1829-1916.
1906-1910
Bowker, Richard Rogers, 1848-1933.
1921-1933
Burton, Clarence Monroe, 1853-1932.
1907-1919
Burton, Marion LeRoy, 1874-1925.
1919-1925
Casey, Genevieve Mary, 1916-
See Michigan State Library, 1961-1967
Clements, William Lawrence, 1861-1934.
1916-1934.
Dana, John Cotton, 1856-1929.
See Newark Public Library, 1907-1929
Frankhauser, Mary E.
See Michigan State Library, 1924-1933
Fyan, Loleta D
See Michigan State Library, 1941-1950
Hubbard, Lucius Lee, 1849-1933.
1919-1933
Hutchins, Harry Burns, 1847-1930.
1911-1930; See also Miscellaneous records, Correspondence, 1910-1920
Kahn, Albert, 1869-1942.
1910-1942
Keating, Charles H.
See Commission on Obscenity and Pornography, 1968-1971
Kelsey, Francis Willey, 1858-1927.
1913-1927; See also Michigan. University. Committee on Near East Research, 1926-1927; and Near East Research, 1923-1927.
Little, Clarence Cook, 1888-1971.
1925-1929
McClure, Grace, 1884-
See Michigan State Library, 1935-1941.
MacLeish, Archibald, 1892-
See Library of Congress, 1940-
Mereati, Giovarmi, Cardinal
See Vatican Library, 1916-1944.
Newberry, Truman Handy, 1864-1945.
1921-1936.
Osborn, Chase Salmon, 1860-1949
1920-1949; See also Michigan State Librarian, 1911.
Osborn, Stella (Brunt), 1894-
1950-1953
Power, Eugene Barnum, 1905-
See Edwards Bros., 1936-1938; Microfilms, 1943-1950; Microfilms, Inc., 1941-1947; Projected Books, Inc., 1944-1950; University Microfilms, Inc., 1937-1967.
Purdy, George Flint, 1905-
See Wayne State University, 1934-1967
Putnam, Herbert, 1861-1955.
See Library of Congress, 1920-1938; and U.S. Library of Congress, 1908-1923.
Robbins, Frank Egleston, 1884-1963.
1922-1954
Rowe, Leo S., 1871-1946.
See Pan American Union, 1927-1942
Ruthven, Alexander Grant, 1882-1971.
1918-1953
Spaulding, Thomas Marshall, 1882-1973.
1922-1959
Spencer, Mary C.
See Michigan State Library, 1909-1923
Spill, William Ambrose, 1876-1941.
1928-1931
Strohm, Adam Julius, 1870-
See Detroit Public Library, 1912-1941.
Tisserant, Eugene Cardinal, 1884-
1926-1947; See also Bishop, William W. - Carnegie Endowment for International Peace, 1926-1930; and Vatican Library, 1916-1944.
Todd, Albert May, 1850-1931.
1907-1931
Ulveling, Ralph Adrian, 1902-
See Detroit Public Library, 1939-1950 and Union Catalogs, 1942-1950
Utley, Henry Munson, 1836-1917.
See Detroit Public Library, 1904-1912.
Vandenberg, Arthur Hendrick, 1884-1951.
See U.S. Congress. Senate, 1929-1948.
Walton, Genevieve M
See Michigan State Normal College, 1920-1930.
White, William Allen, 1868-1944.
1919-1927
Wilson, Halsey William, 1868-1954.
1906-1925